

#### RESEARCHER, TOYOTA CENTRAL R&D LABS., INC

41-1, Yokomichi, Nagakute, Aichi 480-1192, Japan

### About me

Daisuke Inoue is a researcher at Toyota Central R&D Labs,. Inc. He received a B.E. degree in engineering from Osaka University in 2014 and an M.S. degree in informatics from Kyoto University in 2017. He received a Ph.D. degree in mathematical science from the University of Tokyo in 2024. His current research interests include control engineering, multi-agent systems, and swarm intelligence.

# **Experience**

Toyota Central R&D Labs., Inc.

Aichi, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER

Aug. 2017 - Present

- Controller design for very large-scale systems
- · Exploring applications of quantum annealing machines for control engineering

Kyoto University Kyoto, Japan

Teaching Assistant July. 2016 - Mar. 2017

• Teaching Assistant of Complex Analysis Class

Siemens Industry Software N.V.

Leuven, Belgium

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP

July. 2015 - Mar. 2016

• Motion Controller Design for Airbus A330 based on 1-D & 3-D Co-simulation

Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd.

Kobe, Japan

INTERNSHIP

July. 2014

• Development of Nuclear Power Plant Simulator

# **Education**

The University of Tokyo, Japan

PH.D STUDENT Mar. 2024

• Thesis: Numerical Methods for Nonlinear Partial Differential Equations Arising from Large-Scale Multi-Agent Control Problems

Kyoto University Kyoto, Japan

M.S. IN INFORMATICS Mar. 2017

• Thesis: Stability Analysis of Networked Monotone Systems

Osaka University Osaka, Japan

B.S. IN ENGINEERING Mar. 2014

• Thesis: Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization

### **Selected Publication**

JOURNAL (REFEREED)

Traffic signal optimization in large-scale urban road networks: an adaptive-predictive controller using Ising models

IEEE Access

D. Inoue, H. Yamashita, K. Aihara, and H. Yoshida

2024

Partially Centralized Model-Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems

IFAC Journal of Systems and Control

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

A fictitious-play finite-difference method for linearly solvable mean field games

ESAIM: M2AN

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

2023

#### Traffic Signal Optimization on a Square Lattice with Quantum Annealing

D. INOUE, A. OKADA, T, MATSUMORI, K. AIHARA AND H. YOSHIDA

Scientific Reports 2021

### Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

IEEE Control Systems Letters

D. INOUE, Y. ITO AND H. YOSHIDA

2020

### Model Predictive Control for Finite Input Systems using the D-Wave Quantum Annealer

D. Inoue, H. Yoshida

Scientific Reports

2020

Conference (Refereed)

### Stability Analysis of Logit Dynamics with Committed Minority and Internal/External **Conformity Biases**

Proc. 22nd IFAC World Congress

T. Miyano, Y. Ito, D. Inoue, S. Koide, and T. Hatanaka

Yokohama, Japan, 2023

#### Model Predictive Mean Field Games for Controlling Multi-Agent Systems

D. Inoue, Y. Ito, T. Kashiwabara, N. Saito, and H. Yoshida

2021 IEEE International Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics Melbourne, Australia, 2021

### Optimal Transport-based Coverage Control for Swarm Robot Systems: Generalization of the Voronoi Tessellation-based Method

D. INOUE, Y. ITO AND H. YOSHIDA

American Control Conference 2021

New Orleans, USA, 2021

#### Stochastic Self-Organizing Control for Swarm Robot Systems

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, AND H. YOSHIDA

ICSI 2019 Chiang Mai, Thailand, 2019

### Distributed Range-based Localization for Swarm Robot Systems using Sensor-Fusion **Technique**

D. INOUE, D. MURAI, Y. IKUTA AND H. YOSHIDA

SENSORNETS 2019

Prague, Czech Republic, 2020

### Replay attack detection in control systems with quantized signals

K. KASHIMA AND D. INOUE

European Control Conference 2015

Linz, Austria, 2015

Strasbourg, France, 2014

### Stationary performance evaluation of control systems with random dither quantization European Control Conference 2014

K. KASHIMA AND D. INOUE

### Awards\_

- 2024 Dean's Award, Graduate School of Mathematical Sciences, The University of Tokyo
- 2017 Repayment Exemption for Students with Excellent Grades, Japan Student Services Organization
- Best presentation award on The 59th Japan Automatic Control Conference, The Society of Instrument 2016 and Control Engineer
- Research Encouragement Award on The 58nd Annual Conference of the Institute of Systems, Control 2015 and Information Engineers, The Institute of Systems, Control and Information Engineers
- Research Encouragement Award on The 1st Multi-symposium on Control Systems, The Society of 2014 **Instrument and Control Engineers**

## **Grants**

Vulcanus in Europe (15,540 dollars), Selected students get to go to Europe to study the local language, and 2015 to have a working experience by EU-Japan Centre for Industrial Cooperation in Institute for International Studies and Training.